iabc.com 2016-05-10

# Email & Privacy Policy - Communication Professionals | IABC

  * Privacy Policy
  * Email Privacy for Members
  * Email Privacy for Entities

IABC respects your privacy. Across our association, around the world, we will only collect, store and use your personal information for defined purposes. We use your information to support and enhance our relationship with you, for example, to process your purchase, provide service and support, and share product, service and association news and offerings with you. We only share your personal data outside IABC with your consent, as required by law and then only with partners who share IABC’s commitment to protecting your privacy and data. At any time you may contact IABC with any privacy questions or concerns you may have. You also may ask at any time to see the data you have given us and request correction or deletion. We strive to ensure a high level of security and confidentiality.

### PRIVACY AND DATA SECURITY

At IABC, your right to privacy and data security is a primary concern. That’s why, when you visit IABC.com, we help you maintain control over your personal data on the Internet. Below are the guidelines we use for protecting the information you provide us during a visit to our Internet site or when you use our online support offerings such as support applications loaded on your computer

### IABC ONLY ASKS FOR SPECIFIC TYPES OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

In a few areas on our website and online member support tools, we ask you to provide information that will enable us to enhance your site visit, to assist you with technical support issues or to follow up with you after your visit. It is completely optional for you to participate.

For example, we request information from you when you:

  1. Join/Renew Online.
  2. Update your contact information.
  3. Provide feedback in an online survey.
  4. Subscribe to a newsletter or a mailing list.
  5. Fill out a support request.
  6. Purchase a product or attend an event.

In each of the instances above, we may ask for your name, email address, phone number, address, type of business, member preference information, member number, as well as other similar personal information that is needed to register or subscribe you to services or offers. If we ever ask for significantly different information we will inform you. In the case of newsletters or mailing lists, you will be able to “unsubscribe” to these mailings at any time.

### IABC ONLY USES YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION FOR SPECIFIC PURPOSES

The information you provide will be kept confidential and used to support your member relationship with IABC. Among other things, we want to help you quickly find information on IABC.com and alert you to product upgrades, special offers, updated information and other new products and services from IABC. IABC staff who have access to your personal information and prospect information are required to keep the information confidential and not use it for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing for IABC.

In addition, IABC may be required to disclose personal information in connection with law enforcement, fraud prevention, regulation, and other legal action or if IABC reasonably believes it is necessary to do so to protect IABC, its members, or the public.

### YOU CAN OPT-OUT OF RECEIVING FURTHER MARKETING FROM IABC AT ANY TIME

Periodically, we may send you information about various IABC products and services, or other products and services we feel may be of interest to you. Only IABC (or agents working on behalf of IABC and under confidentiality agreements) will send you these direct mailings. If you do not want to receive such mailings, simply tell us when you give us your personal information.

### IABC WILL NOT DISCLOSE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION TO ANY OUTSIDE ORGANIZATION FOR ITS USE IN MARKETING WITHOUT YOUR CONSENT

Information regarding you (such as name, address and phone number) or your order and the products you purchase will not be given or sold to any outside organization for its use in marketing or solicitation without your consent. Your information may be shared with agents or contractors of IABC for the purpose of performing services for IABC only with your consent.

### INTERNET COMMERCE

Online commerce at iabc.com is designed to give you options concerning the privacy of your credit card information, name, address, email and any other information you provide us. IABC is committed to data security with respect to information collected on our site. We offer the industry standard security measures available through your browser called SSL encryption. If at any time you would like to make a purchase, but do not want to provide your credit card information online, you may contact a IABC customer representative over the telephone. Simply call + 1 415.544.4700. It has always been a IABC practice to contact members in the event of a potential problem with your purchase or any normal business communication regarding your purchase.

### CUSTOMIZED EXPERIENCE

We use technology to help us deliver customized visitor experiences. At IABC, we primarily use “cookies” to help us determine which service and support information is appropriate to your machine and to maintain your membership experience online. Our use of this technology does not mean that we automatically know any information about you. We might be able to ascertain what type of computer you are using, but beyond that, our use of cookies is designed only to provide you with a better experience when using IABC.com. IABC has no desire or intent to infringe on your privacy while using the IABC.com site.

### THIRD-PARTY SITES

Please be aware that other web sites that may be accessed through our site may collect personally identifiable information about you. This privacy statement does not cover the information practices of those third-party web sites linked to IABC.com.

You are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords or any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you’re online. If you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. So please use discretion when posting any personal information to public areas of the IABC website.

### CONTACT IABC

IABC is the sole operator of the IABC website. If you would like to contact us for any reason regarding our privacy practices, please write us at the following address:

### INTERNATIONAL ASSOCIATION OF BUSINESS COMMUNICATORS

Attention: Privacy  
155 Montgomery Street  
Suite 1210  
San Francisco, CA 94104 U.S.

Phone: 415.544.4700  
Toll Free: 800.776.4222  
Fax: 415.544.4747

### Overview and Background

Most organizations are in a period of transition today regarding how they manage and use email and related technologies. IABC has faced issues with online postings in the MemberSpeak area of its website for a number of years. In the past, when this area of the site was open to the public, there were problems with vulgar postings. The association’s solution was to move this benefit to the member-only portion of the website after a lengthy absence of the forum altogether. To address issues related to email usage, the board two years ago passed a policy concerning chapters’, districts’, regions’ and international’s publication of email addresses. That policy, however, did not deal with individual members’ use of email and website tools. Recent problems have highlighted the need to spell out unacceptable use of IABC Internet tools and the consequences for inappropriate behaviors.

### Examples of Inappropriate Use

During the past several years, the association has observed these types of inappropriate use of its website:

  * Posting messages that included vulgar, inappropriate, and misleading messages
  * Posting messages that could have been interpreted as official IABC messages

Other examples of inappropriate use that would be defined in a website usage policy are:

  * Posting messages that included vulgar, inappropriate, and misleading language.
  * Posting messages that could have been interpreted as official IABC messages.

Other examples of inappropriate use that would be defined in a website usage policy are:

  * Using Member Search to distribute unsolicited commercial e-mail (UCE), which is commonly known as “spam.”
  * Harvesting e-mail address or other contact information from www.iabc.com or any Chapter or Regional Web sites for purposes of distributing UCE.
  * Sending out any form of promotional communication to our members that implies endorsement by IABC, when no such endorsement exists.
  * Posting messages to any IABC online forum: (a) to promote products or services not endorsed by IABC; and (b) that are threatening, profane, or bigoted in nature.
  * Interfering with or “making mischief” via any present or future IABC online application.
  * Security breaches, including but not limited to, password theft, password sharing, and misrepresenting one’s identity via any present or future IABC online application.

### IABC’s Definition of UCE, a.k.a. “spam”

Because IABC is an association whose members depend on it for networking and support, our definition of UCE, a.k.a. “spam,” may differ from definitions used by commercial organizations. IABC defines UCE as unsolicited commercial email that is sent:

  * To recipients whom the sender does not know personally or with whom the sender does not have an Existing Business Relationship (an example of EBR: chapter leaders emailing their members, association members who provide services and who already have IABC members in their databases)
  * As a mass-marketing type of communication that is not explicitly requested.

### IABC Website User Conduct Policy

We respect and are committed to your privacy while online with IABC. At the same time, we recognize that as communicators and business people, you have a need to share information within the IABC networks. Sharing information is a major benefit of your IABC membership. This website User Conduct policy states our guidelines for site usage, so that all users can have a quality experience online with us.

  * You agree, as a user of our website, to abide by all applicable local, state, national and international laws and regulations in your use of the IABC website (“Service”), and agree not to interfere with the use and enjoyment of the Service by other users
  * You agree to be solely responsible for your actions and the contents of your transmissions through IABC. You agree not to impersonate any person or entity, including but not limited to, an IABC official, forum leader, guide or host or falsely state or otherwise misrepresent your affiliation with a person or entity
  * You agree not to use the Service to collect or harvest personal information about other users
  * You agree not to post, promote or transmit through the Service any unlawful, harassing, libelous, threatening, harmful, vulgar, hateful or otherwise objectionable material of any kind or nature
  * You agree not to advertise or offer to sell any goods or services, or engage in surveys, post or transmit “junk mail”, “spam” or unsolicited mass distribution of email.

IABC may, at its sole discretion, immediately terminate your access to the Service if your conduct fails to conform to these terms and conditions of the Terms. IABC may, but is not in any way obligated to, enforce these Terms against any user.

In order to protect the privacy of members, IABC’s website, www.iabc.com, will provide an “opt out” option allowing members to opt out of email communications. This may include email from IABC about IABC activities or from IABC about other organizations. email addresses for members who “opt out” may not be used for future email communications, based on the opt-out option they choose:

  1. Opt out of receiving all IABC information.
  2. Opt out only of receiving information about other organizations.
  3. Opt out of being listed in the online directory.

Members are encouraged to use www.iabc.com to register their opt-out requests in order to reduce the workload for chapters and regions. International will provide a means for chapter leaders to get up to date opt-in/out lists from the www.iabc.com site.

No IABC entity, including International, chapters or regions, is allowed to publish its members’ email addresses in printed directories or in a visible format on its website unless such a directory is 100% opt-in, meaning that no member is included in same until they have given the IABC entity explicit permission to do so.

IABC will provide blind links to members’ email addresses to facilitate networking, as currently provided on Member Search. Regions and chapters may do the same.

No IABC entity may sell, trade or give away to an outside organization member information that includes email addresses. Any IABC entity may send an email to its members on behalf of another organization, subject to the opt-out option #2 outlined above for third-party communications.

IABC chapters, districts or regions will communicate with their members by using the “email my chapter” feature, which will be available on the Chapter Management section of the website. By using this feature, chapter, district or regional leaders will be able to send emails that will appear to be addressed to only one recipient so that chapter-wide emails will not include email addresses of every member in the “to” field.

While we realize this policy won’t solve member problems with spamming from other organizations, it does ensure that IABC entities are not responsible for generating spam for members.
